Preliminary Guide to the Career and Cooperative Education Center records, 1951-2004 RG0048
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Career and Cooperative Education Center records
1951-2002
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
RG0048
2.25 Linear Feet
Materials in this collection include annual reports, publications, publications scrapbooks, and microfilm. They range in date from 1951-2002.
Acquisition Information
Materials were transferred to the University Archives by the Director of the Career and Cooperative Education Center.
Historical Note
The Career and Cooperative Education Center at The George Washington University is now part of the Career Center at The George Washington University, and serves students and alumni. It has been known as the Career Center since 1993. From 1990-93 it was called the Career and Cooperative Education Center; from 1983-90 it was known as the Career Services Center; from 1968-83 it was known as the Student and Alumni Career Center; and before that the Student Services or Student Placement Office. The Career Center is overseen by the Senior Vice President for Student and Academic Support Services, and promotes effective career planning, teaches job search strategies, and facilitates contacts between GW students, alumni, and prospective employers through its many services. Services include full- and part-time job listings; internship listings; career consulting; workshops (including job search strategies, letters and resumes, and effective interviewing); the career resource room; on-campus recruiting; resume referral; resume critiques; facilitating the federal work-study program; cooperative education; computer and Internet-based job resources; and a credentials service that supports graduate/professional school applications. Cooperative Education is an educational program which integrates academic study with paid, career-related professional experience that applies classroom theory to work settings related to the academic pursuits of the student. N.B. This history note was written in 2005
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include annual reports, publications, publications scrapbooks, and microfilm. They range in date from 1951-2002, and were transferred to the University Archives by the Director of the Career and Cooperative Education Center.
Collection Organization
Organized into two series of Office records.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Foggy Bottom (Washington, D.C.); Students; Internship programs; Careers; Washington (D.C.); Education, Cooperative; Recruiting and enlistment; Vocational guidance; Scrapbooks; Employment; George Washington University--Alumni and alumnae
- Office records, 1951-1988; RG0048 Series 1; 2 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Materials in this collection include annual reports, publications, scrapbooks, and microfilm. They range in date from 1951-88, and were transferred to the University Archives by the Director of the Career and Cooperative Education Center.
  Formerly Acc#54; RG# 6.2.2
  - Publications/ Annual Reports, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Publications, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Publications, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Publications, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Publications, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Annual Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Publications, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Publications, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Annual Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Samp. Career Line, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Annual Report, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Publications, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Annual Report and Publications, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Sample Job Opp. Bulletins, 1978-1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Annual Report, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Materials/ Publications, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Publications, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Annual Reports/ Publicity, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Annual Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Annual Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Career Conference Brochures, 1951-1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Annual Reports, 1951-1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Scrapbook, 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Microfilm, Credentials Backup, 1945-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Office records, 1954-2002; RG0048 Series 2; .25 Linear feet
  Materials in this collection include brochures, pamplets, guidelines for employees, annual reports, guides, flyers, catalogs, and class schedules. They range in date from 1954 to 2002.
  Formerly vertical files
  - Career and Cooperative Education Center, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Career Center, 1992-1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Career Center Guidelines for Student Employees, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Career Services Center, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Career Services Center Annual Reports, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Career Services Center - Guide to Career Services, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Career Services Center - Guide to Career Services, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Career Services Office, 1954-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Career Services Office --Externship Program, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Career Services Office Workshops, Seminars, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Center For Career Education, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Center For Career Education Catalogs, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Center For Career Education Catalogs, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Center For Career Education and Workshops (CCEW), Division Of Continuing Education Brochures, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Center For Career Education And Workshops Catalogs, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Center For Career Education And Workshops Catalogs, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)